Guide to the Ruby Loper slide collection, 1950-1960.
Loper, Ruby slide collection, 1950-1960.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ruby Loper slide collection, 1950-1960
23-16-3265
Ruby Loper.
.8 cubic ft.
Lantern slides.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Black and white glass lantern slides depicting prefabricated housing to room interiors and furniture were used by Loper for teaching and research. Some were made commercially and some taken by Cornell photographer Jon Troy.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Loper was New York state's first female extension architect and worked at Cornell from 1946-1967.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Black and white glass lantern slides depicting prefabricated housing to room interiors and furniture were used by Loper for teaching and research. Some were made commercially and some taken by Cornell photographer Jon Troy.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Loper, Ruby.; Loper, Ruby.; Troy, John.; Cornell University.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Dept. of Housing and Design.
Subjects:
Housing.; Prefabricated houses.; Interior architecture--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Furniture
Series II. Miscellaneous Images
Series III. Exhibit Design: The Museum of Modern Art
Series IV. Prefabricated Homes
Series V. Rooms
Series VI. House Planning, Insulation, Heating, Kitchens
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Furniture
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, N.Y., 001 (050) (Box 2)
    Sofa
    Empire sofa, American, with straight back
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 002 (043) (Box 2)
    Upholstered sofa, camel back
  - Edward Van Altena-71-79 W. 45th St., New York City, 003 (Box 2)
    Chair (in section)
    Modern chair cut in section to reveal details of construction
  - None, 004 (Box 2)
    Multiple tables
    Various types and styles of tables; on the left side: small tables; on the right side: larger tables for dining
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 005 (025) (Box 2)
    Multiple chairs
    Upholstered armchairs, Renaissance, Baroque
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 006 (011) (Box 2)
    Chair
    Armchair, Baroque, caned seat and back
  - None, 007 (Box 2)
    Heppelwhite side chairs, upholstered seats
  - "Extension Teaching", 008 (008) (Box 2)
    American armchairs and side chairs with primarily rush seats; high, straight backs
  - "Extension Teaching"-Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 009 (032) (Box 2)
    Table: two views
    Tea table, scalloped edge, claw and ball feet
  - "Furniture", 010 (Box 2)
    Chairs (2)
    American side chairs with rush seats, straight backs
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 011 (012) (Box 2)
    Upholstered armchair with fringe, Baroque
  - None, 012 (Box 2)
    Side chair, Queen Anne style
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 013 (038) (Box 2)
    Chairs (3)
    Neoclassical side chair and arm chairs
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 014 (038) (Box 2)
    DUPLICATE of 014
    See above
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 015 (033) (Box 2)
    Armchair, Chippendale
  - None, 016 (Box 2)
    Queen Anne style armchairs and side chairs
  - A Rope Tourniquet Holding Glued Members in Place, 017 (Box 2)
    Table
    Wooden side table, square top
  - "Extension Teaching" - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 018 (022, 023) (Box 2)
    Tables (2) in multiple views
    Four round tables; Jacobean table at bottom in two views
  - "Extension Teaching", 019 (020) (Box 2)
    Table-chair
    Table-chair: functions as a table when top is lowered, as a chair when it is raised; round top, one drawer in seat
  - None, 020 (Box 2)
    Tables (2)
    Extended leaf dining tables
  - D. Maple Slat Arm chair. Finials, four slats, lower rungs and six inches of legs restored., 021 (Box 2)
    Maple slat arm chair
  - None, 022 (Box 2)
    Highboy
    Wooden highboy painted or inlaid in high detail scenes, cabriole legs
  - None, 023 (Box 2)
    Multiple dressers and vanities
    Three vanities, six dressers, all wood
  - "Extension Teaching", 024 (017) (Box 2)
    Upholstered wing chair; Queen Anne style side chair
  - "Furniture: Chairs" - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 025 (569) (Box 2)
    Windsor chairs
  - Troy Studio, Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York, 026 (013) (Box 2)
    Side chair, Baroque, with rush seat, caned back
  - "Extension Teaching", 027 (009) (Box 2)
    Multiple Chairs
- Series II. Miscellaneous Images
  - "Over Mantel Arrangement, 001 (001) (Box 1)
    Drawing
    Three different compositions for decoration of a mantel
  - None, 002 (Box 1)
    Photo, black and white
    Image of a framed painting; text is cut off at the side
  - Henry G. Keller: Storm-frightened Animals Under the Big Horse Tent, 003 (Box 1)
    Image of an oil painting with textual description
  - None, 004 (Box 1)
    Image of a framed painting; text is cut off at the top
  - None, 005 (Box 1)
    Image of a framed painting; text is shared with the image on slide 004
  - None, 006 (Box 1)
    Image of a framed painting; text cut off at bottom
  - None, 007 (Box 1)
    Image of same painting as slide 006, different frame; text is cut off at bottom
  - "framing - use of mat", 008 (017) (Box 1)
    Framed painting; same image as that of slide 005
  - "over ornate frame", 009 (018) (Box 1)
    Framed painting; same image as that of slides 006 and 007
  - "suitable frame", 010 (019) (Box 1)
    Framed painting; same image as slides 006, 007, and 009, with a different frame
  - "too heavy frame", 011 (020) (Box 1)
    Framed painting; same image as that of slide 002
  - "suitable frame", 012 (021) (Box 1)
    Framed painting; same image as that of slides 002 and 011, with a different frame
  - None, 013 (047) (Box 1)
    Illustration of various tools for construction
  - A Summer Beam, 014 (048) (Box 1)
  - Dynamic Booklet Cover, 015 (Box 1)
    Graphic
    Image of a cover design called 'catastrophe'; textual praise for the design
  - None, 016 (Box 1)
    Illustration of various bookbinding methods, numbered and labeled
  - None, 017 (Box 1)
    Illustration
    Two German Woodcuts
  - None, 018 (Box 1)
    Illustration with text
    A book page with German illustrations and a column of text
  - None, 019 (Box 1)
    Image of a filing cabinet and other various objects; poor quality
  - None, 020 (Box 1)
    A German Photograph of a person pushing a cart from behind; poor quality
  - None, 021 (Box 1)
    Image of a sculpture or piece of artwork
  - None, 022 (Box 1)
    Image of a hieroglyphic inscription
  - None, 023 (Box 1)
    Image of ancient drawings and a hieroglyphic inscription
  - BLACK-FACE GOTHIC, 024 (Box 1)
    Book page illustrating the Black-Face Gothic font
  - Camel with his driver, 16th century line drawing, 025 (Box 1)
    Image of an ancient illustration
  - Mayan Hieroglyphic Manuscript, 026 (Box 1)
  - None, 027 (Box 1)
    Same image as that of slide 023
- Series III. Exhibit Design: The Museum of Modern Art
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 001 (Box 1)
    Exterior view of the Museum of Modern Art
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 002 (Box 1)
    Exhibit Design: "The Bauhaus Synthesis"
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 003 (Box 1)
    Exhibit Design: "The Early Republic - Houses"
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 004 (Box 1)
    Exhibit Design: "London Transport"
  - "HD 220 Furniture Design, Comfort Angles" - Relaxing, Dressing, 005 (Box 1)
    Image of a woman in different positions for daily activities (relaxing and dressing), exhibited on Alvar Aalto chairs
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C.; Dining, Reading, 006 (Box 1)
    Image of a woman in different positions for daily activities (dining and reading), exhibited on Alvar Aalto chairs
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 007 (Box 1)
    Modern plywood storage unit, displayed with cabinetry held open for viewing
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 008 (Box 1)
    Various stainless steel light fixtures
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 009 (Box 1)
    Exhibit Design; various cultural artifacts
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St., N.Y.C., 010 (Box 1)
    Exhibit Design; outdoor display of cultural artifacts
  - "Exhibit Design - Machine Art Exhibition", 011 (Box 1)
    "Wall composition - Machine Art Exhibit"
  - "Exhibit Design - Machine Art Exhibition", 012 (Box 1)
    "Wall composition - Machine Art Exhibit"; an alternate view
  - "HD 220 - Interior with Furniture", 013 (Box 1)
    "Charles Eames - Living Dining Group"
  - "Exhibit Display - Useful Objects, 1940", 014 (Box 1)
    An exhibit of various potted plants and small statues
  - "Exhibit Design - Free-standing units - 20 Centuries of Mexican Art", 015 (Box 1)
    An exhibit of Mexican Art
  - "Exhibit Display- Table Display - Useful Objects, 1940", 016 (Box 1)
    An exhibit of various everyday objects displayed on tables
  - "Nelson and Wright - Storage Wall - 1944", 017 (Box 1)
    A woman demonstrates the uses of a storage wall on display
  - "Exhibit Design - Table Display - Lighting Emphasis - Useful Objects, 1940", 018 (Box 1)
    A close-up view of the table display and overhead lighting on slide 016
  - "Exhibit Design - Table and Wall - Rhythm in Shape and Size - Installation of a Useful Objects Exhibition at MOMA", 019 (Box 1)
    Table wares displayed against a wall
  - "HD 100 Industrial Design - Function and Form", 020 (Box 1)
    Image of a piece of wood cutting and below it a boat, with a similar shape as that of the wood cutting
  - "HD 100 Industrial Design - Installation View of Art in Progress Exhibition", 021 (Box 1)
    An exhibit of various modern equipment, such as an electric fan, and modern radios
  - "HD 100 Industrial Design - Plastic Dinnerware - Watertown Manufacturing Company", 022 (Box 1)
    A small display of dinnerware, including plates, cups, and saucers
  - "HD 100 Design - 3 Dimensional Composition - Molded Plywood Sculpture", 023 (Box 1)
    An abstract sculpture of molded plywood
  - "Molded Plywood Sculpture", 024 (Box 1)
    Duplicate of 023
  - "HD 220 Furniture Construction - Stacking Chairs - Shaped Plywood", 025 (Box 1)
    Alvar Aalto stacking chairs
  - "HD 220 Furniture Design - Stacking Chairs - Molded Plywood", 026 (Box 1)
    Marcel Breuer stacking chairs
  - "HD 220 Furniture Design", 027 (Box 1)
    Chair by Bruno Matthson; plywood, with webbing
  - "HD 100 Child Art Experience - Children's Circus, 1944", 028 (Box 1)
    Children seated in a row, painting
- Series IV. Prefabricated Homes
  - (Pre-fabricated houses are now in the air), 001 (001) (Box 3)
    Cartoon
    A stork flies over a 'homeless' family with a house carried in its beak
  - Theoretical Savings in Pre-fabrication, 002 (002) (Box 3)
    Text
    Five cost-saving benefits of prefabricated homes
  - Coordination of Men + Materials + Time = Prefabrication, 003 (003) (Box 3)
    Cartoon diagram
    Diagrammatical explanation of how men, materials, and time are the resources for producing prefabricated homes
  - Commercial Standard CS125-47 for Prefabricated Homes, 004 (004) (Box 3)
    Gives a statement of 'purpose' and 'scope'; statements of 'definition' and 'general requirements' are partially cut out
  - None, 005 (005) (Box 3)
    Drawing (pixilated)
    One-story home
  - None, 006 (006) (Box 3)
    Series F1: Photo
    Aerial view of a large factory, the Gunnison Plant, in New Albany, Indiana
  - None, 007 (007) (Box 3)
    Series F2: Photo
    Interior view of men working on factory lines
  - None, 008 (008) (Box 3)
    Series F3: Photo
    Interior view of factory; men and women manufacturing large sheets of plywood
  - None, 009 (009) (Box 3)
    Series F4: Photo
    Interior view of factory; men and women manufacturing wood frames
  - None, 010 (010) (Box 3)
    Series F5: Photo
    Interior view of factory; men and women attaching insulation to sheets of plywood
  - None, 011 (011) (Box 3)
    Series F6: Photo
    Interior view of factory; men using a machine to bond wall panels together
  - None, 012 (012) (Box 3)
    Series F7: Photo
    Interior view of men and women working on factory lines
  - None, 013 (013) (Box 3)
    Series F8: Photo
    Interior view of factory; wall panels attached to an overhead conveyor are inspected
  - None, 014 (014) (Box 3)
    Series F9: Photo
    Interior view of factory; a woman uses a hose to spray paint a wall panel
  - None, 015 (015) (Box 3)
    Series F10: Photo
    Interior view of factory; wall panels are finished and dried
  - None, 016 (016) (Box 3)
    Series F11: Photo
    Interior view of factory; women work on wall panels attached to overhead conveyors; windows are installed in the panels
  - None, 017 (017) (Box 3)
    Series F12: Photo
    Interior view of factory; stacks of walls segments are stored and transported
  - None, 018 (018) (Box 3)
    Series F13: Photo
    Interior view of factory; men manufacturing different sizes of wall panels
  - None, 019 (019) (Box 3)
    Series F14: Photo
    Interior view of factory; men and women prepare and pack construction materials into two large boxes
  - None, 020 (020) (Box 3)
    Photo
    Exterior view of tractor trailers labeled 'Gunnison Homes' lined up outside the factory for loading and shipment
  - None, 021 (022) (Box 3)
    Front elevation; one-story cottage
  - None, 022 (023) (Box 3)
    Side elevation; one-story cottage with screened porch
  - Gunnison Homes, 023 (024) (Box 3)
    View of a one-story cottage; appears to be an advertisement
  - None, 024 (025) (Box 3)
    Floor plan of a one-story home; two bedrooms
  - None, 025 (042) (Box 3)
    Series F15: Photo
    Interior view of factory machinery
  - None, 026 (043) (Box 3)
    Series F16: Photo
    Interior view of factory; large panels being transported along overhead conveyors
  - None, 027 (044) (Box 3)
    Series F17: Photo
    Interior view of factory; small panels moving on a low conveyor
  - None, 028 (045) (Box 3)
    Series F18: Photo
    Interior view of factory; small panels on factory lines
  - None, 029 (046) (Box 3)
    Series F19: Photo
    Interior view of factory; male workers and large machinery
  - None, 030 (049) (Box 3)
    Series C1: Photo
    Men unloading materials from a trailer labeled 'The Lustron Home: a New Standard for Living'
  - None, 031 (050) (Box 3)
    Series C2: Photo
    View of materials gathered at the worksite
  - None, 032 (051) (Box 3)
    Series C3: Photo
    Carpenters begin to erect the frame of the house
  - None, 033 (052) (Box 3)
    Series C4: Photo
    View of the work site as the frame goes up
  - None, 034 (053) (Box 3)
    Series C5: Photo
  - None, 035 (054) (Box 3)
    Series C6: Photo
  - None, 036 (055) (Box 3)
    Series C7: Photo
    View of frame construction of the roof
  - None, 037 (056) (Box 3)
    Series C8: Photo
    View of carpenters attaching installation to the exterior of the frame
  - None, 038 (057) (Box 3)
    Series C9: Photo
  - None, 039 (058) (Box 3)
    Series C10: Photo
    View of carpenters completing the roof
  - None, 040 (059) (Box 3)
    Series C11: Photo
    Interior view of the house in construction; roof not yet completed
  - None, 041 (060) (Box 3)
    Series C12: Photo
    Interior view of carpenters installing ceiling panels
  - None, 042 (061) (Box 3)
    Series C13: Photo
    Interior view of overhead ceiling panels and ceiling construction
  - None, 043 (066) (Box 3)
    Front elevation of one-story cottage
  - None, 044 (067) (Box 3)
    Floor plan of one-story cottage; two bedrooms
  - None, 045 (068) (Box 3)
    Interior view of a living room looking into the kitchen doorway
  - None, 046 (069) (Box 3)
  - None, 047 (074) (Box 3)
    Carpenters completing the exterior of a one-story cottage
  - None, 048 (077) (Box 3)
  - PLAN 100 KD, 101 KD, 049 (078) (Box 3)
    Floor plan of one-story cottage, two bedrooms
  - PLAN 100 U, 101 U, 050 (079) (Box 3)
  - PLAN 100 U, 101 U, 051 (080) (Box 3)
    DUPLICATE OF 050
  - One type of prefabricated wall panel, 052 (081) (Box 3)
    Construction drawing of a wall panel with wood siding
  - None, 053 (082) (Box 3)
    Interior view of factory; men constructing a wall panel
  - None, 054 (083) (Box 3)
    Rendered Drawing
  - None, 055 (085) (Box 3)
    Men pushing a large construction unit into an un-finished house
  - None, 056 (086) (Box 3)
    Perspective view of a back-to-back kitchen and bathroom unit
  - "Have you got one a little larger?", 057 (092) (Box 3)
    Cartoon illustration of a couple searching for a prefrabricated home in a toy store
  - SUGGESTED PROCEDURE FOR BUYING, 058 (093) (Box 3)
    Textual slide with three considerations for buying a prefabricated home
- Series V. Rooms
  - None, 001 (Box 1)
    Bedroom
    Two twin beds; fireplace; high boy dresser; flowery wallpaper, curtains, and rug
  - John Whipple House, Ipswich, Massachusetts; Late Seventeenth Century, 002 (Box 1)
    Probably a Sitting Room/Kitchen
    Large fireplace, decorated mantle; otherwise modest decoration and spare in appearance
  - None, 003 (Box 1)
    Series: DR1 - Formal Dining Room
    Small space; minimal décor; chairs against the wall; polished silver; cheerful; 4 chairs
  - None, 004 (Box 1)
    Series: DR 2 - Dining Room
    Small and minimal; sewing machine against the wall; cheerful; 4 chairs
  - "Extension Teaching", 005 (025) (Box 1)
    Series: DR 3 - Dining Room
    Open entry; relatively minimal; corner cabinet and bookshelves; 4 chairs
  - "Extension Teaching", 006 (003) (Box 1)
    Dining Room
    Large, long dining table; lots of tableware on display
  - "Interior"; TROY Studio Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 007 (Box 1)
    Large space; minimal furniture; exposed-beam ceiling; chairs against the wall
  - "Extension Teaching", 008 (038) (Box 1)
    Motif
    Simple wooden dresser; flanked by chairs of similar style; topped with an arrangement in a vase and a round platter
  - "Extension Teaching", 009 (005, 23, 34) (Box 1)
    Simple wooden dresser and chair; some decoration; striped wallpaper
  - None, 010 (019) (Box 1)
    Series: D1 - Double Image: Side chairs and Secretaries
    Three-drawer secretaries, each with a wooden side chair drawn up to the dropped leaf of the desk; personally decorated
  - "Extension Teaching", 011 (014, 018, 034, 040) (Box 1)
    Possibly an office space
    A secretary and bookcase flanked by a rocking chair on one side and windsor chair on the other; desk under the window along adjacent wall
  - "Grouping"; TROY Studio Lantern Slide Makers, Cornell University, Ithaca, NY, 012 (Box 1)
    Possibly an office or living room
    Secretary and bookcase in similar detail as shown in 011; various side tables and seating
  - "Proportion"; John P. Troy, Sibley College, Ithaca NY, 013 (008) (Box 1)
    Series: T&C1 - Seating arrangement
    Side table flanked by a worn leather armchair and Windsor chair
  - "Extension Teaching", 014 (004) (Box 1)
    Series: DR 4 - Dining Room
    Cheerfully decorated table and four chairs; built-in display shelf
  - "Extension Teaching", 015 (37) (Box 1)
    Part of a bedroom or living room
    Corner of a room showing window seat, Pembroke table, wooden frame loveseat
  - "Extension Teaching", 016 (37) (Box 1)
    DUPLICATE OF 015
  - None, 017 (012, 016) (Box 1)
    Series: DR 5 - Dining Room
    Symmetrical arrangement; dining table at center, flanked by two chairs against the wall, opposing corner cabinets
  - "Extension Teaching", 018 (027) (Box 1)
    Probably part of a Living Room
    Open doorway with view into other spaces; Pembroke table, small rug, Windsor chairs
  - None, 019 (022, 026) (Box 1)
    Fireplace arrangement
    Fireplace flanked by a wing chair and a round side table; mantle minimally decorated
  - None, 020 (Box 1)
    Living Area
    Secretary with bookcase; furniture against the walls; window centered in image
  - None, 021 (009, 013) (Box 1)
    Series: T&C2 - Motif
    Corner of a room with side table and chair; situated at a doorway
  - None, 022 (029) (Box 1)
    Living Room
    Low ceiling; fireplace flanked by armchairs; bookcase; cozy and informal
  - None, 023 (Box 1)
    Series: T&C3 - Living area
    A piece of art overhangs a drop-leaf table; chairs on either side
  - None, 024 (Box 1)
    Series: T&C4 - Living area
    Upholstered armchair and side table with books, lamp
  - None, 025 (Box 1)
    Series: T&C5 - Living area
    Wooden side chair and table with flowers, overhung by a mirror; situated by a doorway
  - Edward Van Altena - 71-79 W. 45th St, NYC, 026 (Box 1)
    Series: MOD1 - Dining area
    Perspective of a dinging table and chairs; bowl of fruit
  - None, 027 (Box 1)
    Foyer and stairs
    Curving banister; side table and chairs, mirror; view into another room
  - "Line", 028 (004) (Box 1)
    Double Image: Living Room
    Same sofa arranged at two different angles
  - "Several textures in picture arrangement", 029 (012) (Box 1)
    Series: D2 - Living/Office area
    Secretary desk, wooden chairs; art on the walls
  - "Bedroom arrangement"; "UNITY", 030 (013) (Box 1)
    Double bed; dresser and mirror; small and minimal
  - "Informal arrangement", 031 (010) (Box 1)
    Series: C1 - Living Area
    Grandfather clock and painting
  - "Informal arrangement", 032 (011) (Box 1)
    Series: C2 - Living Area
    Grandfather clock with painting and wing chair
  - "unity of expression and contrast of detail", 033 (014) (Box 1)
    Series: MOD2 - Living Area
    Modern style chair and cabinetry; painting
  - "connecting drapery for composing arrangement", 034 (015) (Box 1)
    Series: MOD3 - Living Area
    Modern style chair and ottoman with lamp, artwork
  - "Extension Teaching"; "paneled wall and picture", 035 (009) (Box 1)
    Room is dominated by wood furniture and detail; long table and fireplace
  - "unity of design", 036 (016) (Box 1)
    Series: MOD4 - Living Area
    Modern style chair and cabinetry (same as 033); artwork
  - None, 037 (Box 1)
    Surfaces covered in framed photographs; many paintings on the walls; upholstered chair and fireplace
  - "over mantel", 038 (004) (Box 1)
    Fireplace and chairs; mantel decorated minimally
  - "Extension Teaching", 039 (014, 020, 091) (Box 1)
    Series: D3 - Living/Office Area
    Secretary desk and mirror; formally decorated
  - None, 040 (004) (Box 1)
    Series: T&C6 - Motif
    Upholstered armchair and side table
  - "Interiors", 041 (008, 010) (Box 1)
    Single bed arranged against the wall; large piece of fabric artwork overhangs; spare and minimal
  - None, 042 (Box 1)
    Fireplace and built-in cabinetry/bookcase; settee and cushions
  - None, 043 (Box 1)
    Long, skinny wicker table; plants; brick or stone wainscoting; tiled floor
  - "GROUPING", 044 (010) (Box 1)
    Double Image: Motif
    Drop leaf table flanked by chairs with symmetrical candle arrangement; small table with similar candle arrangement
  - None, 045 (Box 1)
    Living/Office Area
    Small table with books under a high, short window; decorated window sill
  - None, 046 (Box 1)
    Informal Eating Area
    'nook' with small, round table; high, short windows
  - None, 047 (Box 1)
    Series: MOD5 - Living Room
    Modern furniture and artwork; minimal
  - None, 048 (Box 1)
    Series: MOD6 - Living Room
    Modern furniture; plants; window provides a view